-=圣城家园 SCG-720PG 荣誉出品=-
打佛 作品
bbs.cnscg.com
日本封建时代的武士 誓言以性命保卫君主
君主被杀是武士的奇耻大辱
他们必须四处流浪 寻找武士、或强盗的工作
这些无主的战士 不再被视为武士
他们有另一个称号 叫作...
《浪人》
[ 巴黎 ]
打烊了
We are closed.
只喝一杯
Just a small drink.
厕所在哪?
The toilets?
喝一杯我就走
A quick drink and then l'll leave.
你为何急着走?
Why are you rushing off?
我问你 为何急着走?
l said, "Why are you rushing off?"
我听不懂
l don't understand.
贝斯特的那个人打电话给你
The man from Bristol called you.
- 什么人? - 那个坐轮椅的人
- What man? - The man in the wheelchair.
你刚才在这做什么?
What were you doing back here?
小姐
Lady,
我不会进自己没把握能出去的地方
l never walk into a place l don't know how to walk out of.
- 你又为何要上车? - 你心里明白
- Then why would you get into that van? - You know the reason.
大家别拘束
Make yourselves at home.
你大老远地赶来 很感激你过来
You've come a long way. Thanks for coming.
什么任务?
What's the job?
有人拿了我们要的东西
There are some people who have something we require.
- 想请你们去拿回来 - 要用硬的?
- And we want you to get it from them. - lt involves shooting?
你们一定是累了
You must be tired.
明天再详谈
We'll tell you more tomorrow.
7个丰年、7个荒年
Seven fat years and seven lean years.
圣经上这么说的
That's what it says in the Bible.
你杀过人吗?
You ever kill anybody?
我曾伤过别人的心
l hurt somebody's feelings once.
我们见过吗?
Don't l know you?
我想没有
l don't think so.
我会记得的
l'd remember.
两小时轮守
Okay. Two- hour shifts.
- 我守前面 - 留着抽
- l'll watch the front. - For later.
你守后面
You guys watch the back.
谢谢
你醒了?
You awake, then?
情形如何?
How we doing?
你是老板还是伙计?
You labor or management?
是老板就不会给烟你抽
lf l was management, l wouldn't have given you a cigarette.
我是导游
l am the tour guide.
那边是艾菲尔铁塔
Over there is the Eiffel Tower.
那边是卢浮宫 那边是厕所
Over here, the Louvre. Over there, les toilettes.
- 怎么称呼? - 我叫文森
- What do l call you? - My name is Vincent.
山姆
Sam.
当初说好的 周薪5000元
As per the agreement, your salary will be $5,000 a week
至少支付4周
with a minimum of four weeks' work.
成功完成任务后
On the successful completion of the mission
每人分红...
you will each receive a bonus
2万酬金
of $20,000.
我叫黛卓
And by the way, my name is Deirdre.
- 工作大纲是... - 你老大是谁?
- The broad outlines of the mission are... - Who are your principals?
我就是你老大
For you there's no one but myself.
小妞 你能提供什么?
And what can we infer from your charming lrish lilt?
一切所需
Anything you like.
装备在哪?
Where's the equipment?
列出需要的装备 交给文森
Tell me what you need. Make a list and give it to Vincent.
- 有些科技装备很难搞到 - 只要巴黎有 我就能弄到
- Some of the equipment is quite technical. - lf it's in Paris, l'll find it for you.
我们要找的就是这个箱子
This is what we're after.
箱子不能损坏 对方有戒备
We need to take it intact from several men who'll be intent on preventing us.
- 多少人? - 你是美国人?
- How many men? - You American?
我猜人数不多 5到8人
l think the group would be quite small. Between five and eight.
不超过8个人
No more than eight.
你是猜的 你不确定?
So you would think. You don't know for sure?
行动前我会弄清楚
l don't know now, but l will know before the event.
若你不知道 为何认定5到8人?
lf you don't know, why do you say between five and eight?
他们开2、3辆车 经常迁移
Because there's two to three cars. The group's traveling.
- 他们不在巴黎? - 不在
- They're not in Paris? - No.
- 在哪? - 你很快就知道
- Where are they? - You'll find out soon enough.
箱里装什么?
What's in the case?
我们目前计划伏击
Our plan, in the broad strokes, is an ambush.
伏击他们的车队
lt's to hit the car, to take them in transit.
车队? 市区或郊区?
Transit? City, country?
目前不确定
Right now, as l said, l don't know.
行动要快 看情况而定
But we have to move very quickly. We have to improvise.
我们从这开始 先伏击2、3辆车
We'll start with this: Ambush and assault on two to three vehicles,
5到8人 目标是安全取回箱子
five to eight men, and our objective is the safe retrieval of this case.
将所需装备 告诉文森
Tell Vincent what it is you'll need.
对方是什么人? 法国人?
What do we know about them? Are they French?
是何方神圣?
Where are they from? Who are they?
只要记住 他们不是善男信女
All you need to know right now is that they're very unpleasant.
- 以前干过这种事吗? - 没有
- You've done this kind of thing before? - No.
会有多难?
How difficult can it be?
对方有什么武器?
We have no idea how these men will be armed?
他们火力强大
We'll assume they'll be very well armed, indeed.
我们去哪? 怎么回来?
Where are we going and how are we getting back from there?
会在法国 于休闲车处集合与撤退
lt'll be in France, and the group will disband at the RV point.
- 什么意思? - 得手后 各自逃逸
- What does she mean? - After that, we're on our own.
- 军事术语 - 对
- lt's a military term. - That's right.
赖利 告诉文森 你要什么?
Larry, can you tell Vincent what it is you'll need?
速度很快的奥迪S- 8
Something very fast. Audi S8.
能在公路称霸
Something that can shove a little bit.
下午前给你
l'm going to have it for you by the afternoon.
要氮化燃油系统 我有规格
l'm also gonna need a nitrous system. l've got the specs.
你需要什么武器?
What do you use, weapons- wise?
我是武器专家
Weapons. l'm a weapons man.
- 武器专家? - 对
- Weapons man? - Yeah.
太好了
Okay.
有武器就能搞定 你喜欢什么?
They tend to settle the argument. So what do you favor?
武器是工具 无所谓
lt's a toolbox. l don't care.
- 工具就是为了干活而已 - 什么?
- You put the tools in for the job. That's all. - What?
我喜欢美军制式手枪
You know, l actually favor the old 1911.
45口径? 旧式的
Forty- five? Old gun.
保国卫民 功不可没
lt served my country well. A long time.
保个屁 美军表现不佳
Your country. Not done too well though, have you?
- 在过去几场战役中 - 也许
- Last few wars? - Perhaps not,
但没什么好抱怨的
but at least we don't go around whining about it.
你是退役军人?
You ex- military?
我是看报纸应徵的
No, l got my job through The New York Times.
别被他惹火了
Don't let him get you down.
我才不在乎
lt don't mean nothing to me.
我直言直说
l say what l think.
你是退役军人?
You ex- military?
特种部队?
Or is it Hereford?
对不起 我想重提 在哪里撤退?
l'm sorry, but l like to do it backwards. The line of retreat is?
她说了 在休闲车处集合 然后解散
She just told you. We meet back at the RV, disband.
我明白 我只是想弄清楚对方的状况
l understand. l'm just trying to get a vague notion of the opposition.
我开始有些恐惧感 而且...
l mean, we're setting out to cause some animosity over here, and l...
会有多少人追杀我们?
Who and how many are going to be coming after us?
你怕死?
You worried about saving your own skin?
对 死了没戏唱
Yeah, l am. lt covers my body.
出发前会给你答案
All your concerns will be addressed before we leave.
- 通讯器材 - 最多3辆车?
- Electronics and commo. - Not more than three cars?
这是据我所知
That is our information.
- 我要枪响弹 - 那是什么?
- Can you get me a simulator? - What's a simulator?
枪弹火药 没子弹只有枪声
Gunpowder. Sound only, no lead. Sounds like a pistol, an assault rifle.
用于分散对方的注意力
Quite diverting.
我要高速喷射引擎
Listen, l'm also going to need some bigger injection jets.
一般货不行 要订做的
The Bosch is not going to do it. Must be custom made.
往南或往北?
Are we going north or are we going south?
- 我要2根氮化燃油管 - 我认识一个人
- And l'm gonna need two nitrous tubes. - l know a guy.
- 我还要些新衣服 - 文森会处理
- l'd like some new clothes. - Vincent will sort you out.
交给我办
l'll take care of it.
- 怎会找上你? - 另一人身体不适
- So what brought you here? - A fellow that doesn't work so well.
坐轮椅的人?
The man in the wheelchair?
怎么受伤的?
How did he get there?
上次在你地盘
Seems to me that was in your neck of the woods
受的伤
back in the late unpleasantness.
反应真快
Good reflexes.
没错
Yeah.
他们顽强抵抗
They die hard.
- 逼供 - 什么?
- lnterrogation. - What?
对付逼供的方法
Methods to withstand interrogation.
你受过训?
You've done that?
知道如何打死不招
We were taught to hold out indefinitely.
没人做得到
Nobody can hold out indefinitely.
- 是吗? - 对 人都有极限
- ls that so? - Yeah. Everybody has a limit.
我曾被逼供
l spent some time in interrogation, once.
- 他们严刑逼供? - 至少不是闹着玩
- They make it hard on you? - They don't make it easy.
很不好受的
Yeah, it was unpleasant.
我极力忍耐 但他们不择手段
l held out as long as l could. All the stuff they tried.
你不可能不招 办不到
You just can't hold out forever. lmpossible.
- 最后怎么招了? - 他们给我蚱蜢
- How'd they finally get to you? - They gave me a grasshopper.
什么蚱蜢?
What's a grasshopper?
琴酒加白兰地
Let's see. That's two part gin, two part brandy,
利口酒...
one part creme de menthe and...
真聪明
Fucking smart ass.
- 能找到这地方吗? - 当然
- Can you find this place? - Of course.
我知道
l know it.
在那里交易武器
That's where they wanna do the exchange.
现金交易?
You're gonna exchange for cash?
- 对 - 你认识这些人?
- Aye. - You know these people?
我手下认识
My people know them.
你手下曾与他们交易过?
Your people have done business with them before
还是他们只有你手下的电话号码?
or these people just gave your people a number?
赖利
Larry.
好的
Okay.
要做就别迟疑
lf we're gonna do it, let's do the goddamn thing right.
- 嘿 - 我在忙
- Hey. - l'm busy.
我们走
Okay, come on. Let's go.
我回来会给你答案
The answers to your questions l'll know when l get back.
- 我跟你去 - 你跟他们去
- l'll go with you. - Go with them.
她替谁工作?
Who's this girl work for?
替很有能力的人
Well, she works for our "betters."
知道这些就够了
lt seems that's what we're meant to know.
总是等待的游戏
Always a waiting game.
- 什么? - 等待的游戏
- What? - lt's a waiting game.
拜托 别点烟
Would you not do that, please?
会模糊视线是吗?
Bad for the night vision, yeah?
他们来了
There they are.
- 你有清单? - 在我这里
- You have the list? - Yes, l have it.
给我
Give it to me.
钱?
Money?
好了 听我的指挥
Okay. You follow my lead.
记得掩护我
Just make sure you watch my back.
别轻举妄动
Don't make any sudden moves.
买枪不代表我们没枪
Just because we're buying guns doesn't mean we didn't bring any.
别担心 没事
Don't worry. Everything's fine.
要去支援他吗?
You want to back him up?
你死了我有好处吗?
What would l profit from your death?
- 你能得到钱 - 钱已经在我手上
- Well, you'd have the money. - l have the money already.
我守后面
l'll watch the back.
- 货带来了? - 是的
Have you got it all?
- 确定? - 当然 过来看
- You're sure? - Of course. Come and see.
在这里
There it is.
货不齐全
lt's not all here.
- 文森 - 什么?
- Vincent. - What?
货不够
lt's not all here.
怎么回事?
他说其余的货在另一辆车上 但他们老板要先看钱
He said the rest is in the other car. The boss wants to check the money.
看到钱就交货 车匙拿去
lf he agrees, we have no problem. Here, take the car keys.
来 拿去
Go on. Take them.
拿去 别担心
There you are. No problem.
来 跟我来
Come along. Come on.
好吧 先给我些钱
Okay. Give me some of the money.
给钱我
Give me some of the money.
- 好的 - 你不会去吧?
- Okay. - You aren't going in there?
我去 你们跟着
Yeah, l'm going in there. So are you.
- 我去干嘛? - 保护我
- Why am l going in there? - Why? To protect me.
没有保护
There is no protection there.
保护什么? 是陷阱就死定了
lf it's a come- on, we're fish in a barrel.
他们要你去干嘛?
What are you doing? Why do they want you in there?
- 疯了? - 你顾虑太多
- What are you, crazy? - You think too hard.
没人这样跟我说过 但我不会进去
Nobody ever told me that before, but l wouldn't go in there.
- 怎么了? - 不对头 你看
- What is it, Sam? - l don't like it. Look at it.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
我们快点过去 完成交易 好吗?
Okay, let's just do it. Lets just do it and be done, yeah?
别过去
You don't want to go in there.
受雇于人 身不由己
l'm getting paid to go. lt's that simple.
- 好了 走吧 - 若发生情况
- Okay, come on. Let's go. - lf anything goes down
混入对方
get next to one of those guys.
若有狙击手 他怕会伤害到自己人
lf there's a sniper, he'll be afraid to shoot his own guy.
- 走了 - 好的
- Let's go. - All right.
站住!
Stop!
留在原地
Stay where you are.
好了 没问题
So, everything's fine.
我看不见!
Shit, l can't see! l can't see!
你们找死!
Come on! Have some of this!
混蛋!
Fucking have some!
宰了他们!
Fucking have some more!
快!
Come on!
- 走了 - 该死的...
- Let's go! - You goddamn...
快走!
Come on! Let's go!
- 有人受伤吗? - 没事
- Anybody hurt? ls anybody hurt? - We're fine.
噢 那帮混蛋被我们打成果酱
Almost a bit of raspberry jam back there?
稀烂的果酱
A bit of raspberry jam back there.
货到手 钱也在 任务完美达成
Got the swag, kept the money. Job well done.
太好了 太好了
That's a fact. That is a fact.
慢点 慢点
Slow down. Slow down. Slow down.
我有点不舒服
l think l have to stop.
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎会加入的?
Why did you take this job?
我需要钱
My friend, l need the money.
钱在这
The money is here.
什么都是为了钱
That's what this is, you know? Money.
但谁是老板?
Yeah, but who are our employers?
有道理
You're right.
让一下
Excuse me.
先生 让一让
Excuse me, monsieur.
俄国人也想要箱子
The Russians are trying to bid for the case.
箱子在尼斯 他们设法将它卖给俄国人
The case is in Nice. They're trying to sell it to the Russians.
他们住在尼斯的"贝拉默饭店"
They're staying at the Villa Belle Mer in Nice.
- 小组还没准备好? - 不管小组怎样 快行动
- The team isn't ready. - Whatever the team is, you do it now.
俄国人想买 我们要先下手为强
The Russians have decided to bid. We need to move now.
让一下
Excuse me.
我刚接获情报 我们即将
l have the information. We'll be moving very soon.
以埋伏的方式
lt'll definitely be in the nature of an ambush
在这两处附近下手
somewhere between here and here.
预计有3辆车和护卫保镖
We'll anticipate a three- car convoy with a backup team.
我们要在路上拦截
And obviously we will try and stop the target before they can get away from us.
- 箱子里装什么? - 你们不必知道
- What's in the case? - That information isn't necessary.
箱子重吗? 会爆炸? 要铐在手上?
ls it heavy, is it explosive, is it chained to some unlucky bloke's wrist?
- 要剁掉手... - 好了
- Are we gonna have to chop it off... - All right.
我没必要让你们知道...
But l am not under any obligation to let you know...
如果不 那价钱要提高
lf you are not, then the price has got to go up.
你会拿到箱子 但金额要提高
l'll get you the case, but the price has got to go up.
若是这么不专业 我要10万元
lf it's going to be amateur night, l want $100,000. l want it up front.
存入户口 等你箱子到手 再付10万
l want it in a bank account. l want another $100,000 when you get the case.
好的
Okay.
狙击手守在
We've got shooters here,
这两处
shooters here.
- 老战略 - 嘿
- l'll tell you an old trick. - Hey.
- 你干嘛? - 再画一次
- What's your problem? - Draw it again.
再画一次 战略高手 再画一次
Draw it again. You're the ace field man. Draw it again.
图很简单 将你刚才看到的再画一次 再画一次
lt's a simple diagram. Just draw it again. Draw what you saw.
再画一次!
Draw it again!
两名狙击手 车子经过
Two shooters. Car comes through here.
狙击手互射身亡
Shooters across from each other, kill each other dead.
天啊 哪学的?
Oh, my! Where'd you learn that?
- 军中 - 哪个单位?
- ln the regiment. - What regiment was that?
特种部队
The 22nd Special Air Service.
"赫里福船库"什么颜色?
What's the color of the boathouse at Hereford?
我不喜欢你这种态度...
l don't like your attitude...
"赫里福船库"什么颜色?
What's the color of the boathouse...
- 闭嘴! - 什么颜色... 你有枪 我没枪
- Fuck off! - What's... You got the gun. l'm unarmed.
有种就毙了我
Do something. Go ahead. Do something.
谈什么伏击?
Tell me about an ambush? Tell me about an ambush?
我用咖啡就能摆平你
l ambushed you with a cup of coffee.
一手交钱 一手交货
You'll get your money when we get the case.
- 全部有份 - 我知道
- The others too. - That is what l understood.
收到指示 即刻行动
Come on, we've gotten the word. We're moving.
往前移一点
Put this near the front.
当心!
Careful!
当心点
Careful with that.
"赫里福船库"什么颜色?
So what color is the boathouse at Hereford?
我怎么知道?
How the fuck should l know?
这是你的酬劳
This'll complete your compensation.
多谢参与 我们走后 你再离开
Thanks for your time. Feel free to leave when we're gone.
我应该建议你忘了我们吗?
Do l need to suggest that you forget us?
因为我们不会
Because we will not forget.
[ 尼斯 ]
早
'Morning.
你在温习计划?
l see you're reviewing our problem.
对 成于勤奋
Yeah, either you're part of the problem or you're part of the solution
败于怠惰
or you're just part of the landscape.
- 没错 - 箱里装什么?
- lndeed. - What's in the case?
我们要的东西
Something we're paying you for.
- 你跟那女的在饭店前 - 我叫黛卓
- You and the girl are in front of the hotel. - The name's Deirdre.
黛卓 在门外等目标
Deirdre. Wait outside the hotel for the target.
他在饭店、别墅两头跑
He leaves the hotel for the villa, the villa for the hotel.
他上车后会用手机通话 你怎么知道
He activates his cell phone. How do you know he's gonna use his cell phone?
- 我就是知道 - 何以见得?
- He'll use a phone. - How do you know?
我会打给他
l'm gonna call him on it.
- 怎知他带手机? - 因为他在等电话
- How do you know he'll have it with him? - He's waiting for a call.
他以电话
The people he's doing business with
联络接头地点
will call him to tell him the location of the meet.
- 好了吗? - 好的
- Okay? - Okay.
别墅、饭店、车、红绿灯、8到10人...
The villa, the hotel, the car, the stoplight, eight to 10 guys...
戒备森严吗?
How good's the security?
- 不知道 - 他们在哪?
- l can't tell you. - Well, let's find out. Where are they?
最后报告他们在饭店
Last report, they were at the hotel.
- 箱子也在饭店? - 应该是
- The case is at the hotel? - We presume that it is.
- 真有意思 - 何不现在下手?
- That's interesting. - Why don't we do it now?
有道理
lt's tempting.
按照计划行事
lt's a good plan. Let's stick to the plan.
大家都想参与 却没人想善后
Everybody wants to go to the party. Nobody wants to stay and clean up.
拜托
Please.
问题是地图不够精确
The only thing is that the map, the map is not the territory.
去现场看
Let's go look at the ground.
带些钱去购物
Bring some money. We're gonna do a little shopping.
放松点
Listen up.
老婆 装像一点
You're my wife. Maybe you want to look like it.
只是一场戏 演场戏
lt's just a game. Just a game.
一对恩爱夫妻散步 很容易
Man and woman going for a walk and all that that entails. Piece of cake.
放松、放松 亲爱的
Relax. Relax, darling.
你打扮起来很漂亮
You look good cleaned up.
这家饭店?
That's the hotel?
出租车
Taxi.
挽着我的手 快
Put your arm under mine. Put your arm under mine.
为何他们不在别墅 而在这里?
So why aren't they at the villa? Why are they down here?
找乐子、啤酒、女人?
Fun and games? Pretty girls and beer or what?
欢迎光临 开房?
Can l help you, sir?
不 我们看看菜单
We're just looking at the menu.
对不起 会说英语吗?
Excuse me. Do you speak English?
会一点
A little.
能帮我们拍照吗?
Could you take a picture of me and my wife?
很简单 只要按这里
lt's very easy. You press like that.
- 很简单 - 好
- Very easy. - Sure.
对准焦距 就这样
Like that. That's it. Focus like that. Okay?
- 我们拍这里 - 好的
- We're gonna do it over here. - Okay.
- 看 能照到棕榈树吗? - 可以
- Could you get that palm tree in? - Yeah.
我们要渡假胜地的风光
We wanna show we're on the Riviera.
再见
Bye now.
- 拍几张? - 多拍几张
- How many do you want? - Just snap away.
非常好
Very good.
再一张
Again.
要拍下背景
Again. Get the background.
帮我太太拍几张独照
Take a couple of my wife. Just take a couple of my wife, alone.
严禁停车
NO TRESPASSlNG
快拿行李来
Take my luggage up right away.
谢谢
Thank you.
你能和我太太合照一张吗?
Can we take one picture of you with my wife? One picture with you?
就这样
That's it.
怎么样?
So?
很好
They're good.
一个拿箱子 另一个保护主子
A guy goes for the case, the other guy's protecting the principal.
不惊慌 非常优秀
Nobody panics. They're good.
现在怎办?
So what have we learned?
计划可行吗?
Can it be done?
可行 但要多派两个人手
lt can be done. We should have two more men.
没多余人手
We don't have two more men.
去接洽
Go to your handler.
- 没人可接洽 - 我去
- There is no handler. - Let me go.
无人可接洽 只有我
There's no handler. There's only me.
听着 要箱子
Listen, you want this thing, you want the case,
就要增加人手
we're gonna need some more men.
没人手可叫 你害怕?
There's no more help. There's no more men. Are you afraid?
当然害怕 你以为说笑?
Of course l'm afraid. You think l'm reluctant because l'm happy?
我们必须按照计划进行
We've made a good plan, and we're gonna stick with it.
怎么办?
What do we do?
等待
We wait.
他们是谁?
So who are they?
衣食父母
Our employers.
是我
lt's me.
他们回别墅了
They've gone back to the villa.
- 他们带着箱子? - 对
- Did they have the case with them? - They did.
- 车子备妥了? - 是
- Did you get the other cars? - Got them.
- 性能如何? - 很好
- And how do they run? - They'll do fine.
是我
Yeah.
什么意思?
What does that mean?
终于要行动了
lt would be nice to do something.
等待就是行动
We are doing something. We're sitting here, waiting.
今天不能行动
lt's not gonna happen today.
买主出城了
The buyers are out of town.
最早也要明天
Tomorrow at the earliest.
我决定了 去监视他们
You know what? The hell with it. Let's go put them to bed.
我们拿到报告
We've got the report.
那报告是狗屁 我要亲自确定情况
l take the report. l got nothing else. l can go and see for myself.
时不我待 他们在别墅?
lf l don't go, then what am l? They at the villa?
我去现场走一趟
All right, l'm gonna go take one last run over the route and tuck them in.
我跟你去
l'll come with you.
你怎么会从事这一行?
So how'd you get started in this business?
被有钱的混蛋耍了
A wealthy scoundrel seduced and betrayed me.
跟我一样 不是吗?
Same with me. How about that?
拿出地图 要是有人看 我们就...
Take out the map. lf anybody looks, we're...
他们是什么来头?
So who are those guys inside?
你说呢?
You tell me.
退役军人、前秘密警察之类的
Ex- military, Northern Sov Block, somebody or other.
讨生活、混饭吃
Need a job. That's my excuse.
是吗?
ls it?
警察
The cops.
系统启动
System activated.
系统测试
System check.
重复系统测试
Repeat system check.
他在那 正在讲电话
There he is. He's being a good little boy. He's activated his phone.
[ 尼斯 ]
我已就位
l'm in position.
车队通行
They're passing me now.
目标上路了
Target is on the way.
圣诞节还要工作
Hell of a time to be working.
想要什么圣诞礼物?
What do you want for Christmas?
两颗门牙
My two front teeth.
祝你达成心愿
May your wish be granted.
目标离红绿灯400公尺
Target is 400 meters from the traffic light.
快 快!
Come on! Come on!
目标进入预定路线 情况一切良好
So far, so good. Target on the right road.
护送车队
Sam, escort car.
很快就到你那了
Four- tenths of a click in front of you.
知道了
Got it.
赖利 4秒后
Larry, you should see them in four seconds.
出现两部车
Two cars.
看到了
l got them.
目标逃逸 重复 目标逃逸
Target has escaped. l repeat: Target has gotten away.
目标驶往旧城
Target heading for Vieux Nice.
穿过市场 直走
Through the market, then straight.
在马热消岔路 右转
Right at the fork, Marechal fork.
好 你超越他们了
Okay, you're in front of him.
进行拦截
You can cut him off at the end of the port.
收到 知道了
Roger that. l got it.
目标在右方
He's coming from the right.
他是你的了
He's yours.
- 我中弹了 拿箱子 - 绕到另一边去!
- l'm hit! Take the case! - Up the other way!
拿箱子!
Get the fucking case!
上车 回头见!
Get the car at the other end! We'll meet you up there!
- 拿去 - 好
- Take it. - All right.
快走!
Get out of here!
仓库碰头!
l'll see you at the safe house!
箱子给我!
Get rid of the case!
葛格呢?
Where is Gregor?
他窝里反
Gregor fucked us.
- 情况如何? - 到处是警察 还好吗?
- How is it down there? - A lot of heat. How do you feel?
- 还好 谢谢 - 别客气
- Okay. Thanks for before. - Don't mention it.
帮我把油漆擦一下
Could you clean the paint off this?
- 有烟吗? - 你抽太多了
- You got a pack of Camels in there? - No, you smoke too much.
必须离开这里
We must get out of here.
我们需要支援
l'm gonna need your people to help us.
- 要你去找箱子 - 去跟老板说
- And l need you to find the case. - All right, call your guy.
- 拿到箱子就有援助 - 如何取回箱子? 箱子已不见了
- When we bring in the case, he'll help you. - How can l bring in the case?
在葛格手上
Gregor has it.
- 为何? - 我想可能卖给俄国人
- Why? - l presume to sell it to the Russians.
为何卖给俄国人? 怎么不卖给你?
Why the Russians? Why not you?
我有钱买的话 那还找你们干嘛?
lf we had the money to buy the case, we wouldn't have hired you to steal it,
是吗?
would we?
- 跟老板联络 - 要箱子?
- Go to your people. Talk to them. - You want the case?
- 找到葛格就有箱子 - 怎么找葛格?
- lf we find Gregor, we find the case. - How do we find Gregor?
当初怎么找上他帮忙?
How did you find him in the first place? How did you hire him?
从你的跛脚朋友
l found him through your friend, the cripple,
给我的烂名单
who gave me nothing but a bunch of fucking lames!
找来了一群废物!
You and Spence and the whole sorry lot of them.
喂!
Hey!
打手机能找到他
We can find him through his cell phone.
能追踪他的电话吗?
Can we trace his cell phone?
只要有装备
l can triangulate it.
- 就能追查得到 - 谁有装备?
- lf we had that equipment. - Who has that equipment?
谁有装备?
Who has that equipment?
告诉我
Tell me.
谁才有?
Who has it?
好吧 好吧
All right. All right.
给我他的电话号码
Give me the number to his phone.
- 今天好吗? - 法文的回答是
- So how does the day find you? - How do they say it in French,
"我很好"
en pleine forme?
老友见面 何必带枪?
This was supposed to be a social occasion.
- 世事难料 - 的确
- Life is uncertain. - lt is indeed.
葛格 咱们是老交情
But, Gregor, we have so much history together
我想你不会介意
l was sure you wouldn't mind.
目前的局势很...
Besides, the world these days is so...
- 恶劣? - 没错
- Unsafe? - Exactly.
让你见识有多恶劣
l'll show you how unsafe it is.
看到那个女孩吗?
See that little girl down there?
你疯了?
Have you lost your mind?
- 为何这么做? - 表明态度
- Why did you do that? - To make a point.
虽然我不认识她 我还是打算杀掉她
l don't know her, but l was ready to splatter her brains all over the playground.
更何况
But you,
我并不喜欢你
l don't particularly like you.
别轻举妄动 把钱给我
Just imagine what l'll do to you, if you try anything. Now give me my money.
枪放下
Put down the gun.
- 我也不喜欢你 - 哪来的枪?
- l never liked you either, Gregor. - Where did that come from?
- 该脱光了搜 - 箱子呢?
- l should have made you strip. - Now where's my package?
在后座
lt's right behind you.
聪明的女孩
Clever girl.
- 喜欢吗? - 太棒了
- You liked it? - My little sun.
我好开心
You make me so happy.
小宝贝
My sweet love.
抱歉
Excuse me.
办好了?
ls it done?
办好了 米基
lt's done, Mikhi.
葛格? 是你吗?
Gregor? ls that you, Gregor?
- 让你大失所望 - 那只是意外
- Much to your disappointment, no doubt. - lt was a mistake.
真不应该发生
lt should not have happened.
再发生 我卖给爱尔兰人
Well, if it happens again, l'll turn around and sell it to the lrish.
别这样
Don't do that.
别逼我
Then don't make me.
价码提高3倍
My price just went up 300%.
我要箱子
l want the package, Gregor.
- 怎样才能得到? - 等我电话
- What do l have to do to get it? - Just wait for my next phone call.
我会安排细节
l'll find a place where l can tilt the field in my favor.
抱歉...请问一下
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
邮局怎么走?
Could you tell me how to find a post office?
我们认识? 抱歉 我认识你吗?
Do l know you? l'm sorry, do l know you?
你怎知道我会英语?
Because how did you know l speak English?
- 你拿着英文报纸 - 抱歉
- You got an English newspaper. - Sorry.
- 真抱歉 - 没事
- l'm sorry. l beg your pardon. - lt's all right.
为何找邮局? 此地邮局
What do you need a post office for? Because over here,
- 有很多种类 - 我需要帮助
- they use it for different things. - l need your help.
- 辞职了? - 没错
- l thought you left. - l did leave.
- 辞职? 不干了? - 没错
- You did leave? You're out? - That's right.
能帮我吗? 我需要你的帮助
Can you help me? l need your help.
电话号码多少?
What's the number?
- 邮局在左边 - 左边?
- The post office is just down to your left. - Up on the left?
- 左边 - 谢谢你
- On the left. - Thanks.
- 你朋友? - 对 高中同学
- A friend of yours? - Yeah. We went to high school together.
需要帮助时 朋友都跑光了
Everyone's your brother until the rent comes due.
可不是?
Ain't that the truth?
在前廊?
On the terrace?
我的正对面? 我看到他了
Facing me? l see him.
我叫他 请稍候
Yes, l'll get him. Hang on, please.
抱歉 你是山姆先生 对吗?
Excuse me, sir. Are you Sam?
是的
Yeah.
你的电话
A phone call for you.
好久不见 若他转移阵地 我会通知你
Yes, it's good to see you too. lf his position changes, l'll let you know.
葛格在阿尔勒镇
Gregor's in a town called Arles.
他在竞技场
He's at the arena.
这是阿尔勒圆形剧场
So, this is the amphitheater of Arles
西元1世纪兴建
which was built at the end of the first century A.D.
建材为石灰石
lt is built with limestone.
我认识他们
l know those men.
你们可以看到大部分
lt's inspired by this painting and you can see this dominant yellow color
是提灯熏成的黄色
which is actually caused essentially by a lantern.
不确定是不是黄
We're not sure that the walls were actually yellow.
接下来参观罗马浴池
And so now, we will continue and visit the Roman baths down this way.
是我
Yeah.
谢谢各位
Thank you, gentlemen. That'll do nicely.
- 瑟格 我记得你 - 葛格 是我
- lt's Sergi. l remember you. - Yes, Gregor, it's me.
- 你好吗? - 还行
- How've you been? - Well,
时机不好 对于上次的事我很抱歉
these are trying times. l'm sorry about the unfortunate incident.
- 是吗? - 太极端
- Oh, yeah. - lt was excessive.
- 而且太愚蠢 - 说得没错
- And, more to the point, it was foolish. - l couldn't agree with you more.
米基没跟我商量 就采取行动
Mikhi did it without consulting me.
肆无忌惮 嚣张妄为?
Yeah, he's turned rogue and can't be controlled, is that it?
- 我听不懂 - 说英文 抱歉
- l don't... - Oh, English. Sorry.
我刚刚脑残了 我要找梵高故居
Such a fool. l was looking for van Gogh's old house.
原来可以办好的事
So what could've been conducted in a collegial atmosphere
现在却搞砸了 怎么办?
is now fucked into a cocked hat. What do you think?
照你开的价
l think we'll meet your price.
行
Yeah, so let's see it. Let's see it now.
在哪? 在皮带里? 现在看
Where do you have it, in your belt? Let's see it.
先给我看箱子
Show me the case first.
你也许反应灵敏
You're great in the locker room, pal, and your reflexes might die hard,
但不够聪明
but you're weak when you put your spikes on.
- 葛格 没事吧? - 葛格没事
- Gregor, are you all right? - Gregor's fine.
但你们有麻烦了
But l think you're in a wee spot of trouble.
- 箱子在哪? - 我没带来
- Where is it? Where is it? - l don't have it with me.
- 在哪? - 我寄给自己
- Where? - l mailed it to myself.
- 在哪? - 我巴黎的信箱了
- Where is it? - Post office box in Paris.
救命 有人抢劫!
Help! He's robbing me!
站住
Stop.
- 在哪见过? - 维也纳
- Where do l know you from? - Vienna.
对了 抱歉了
Of course. Sorry to have to do this.
- 天呀 - 开车
- Christ. - Drive.
停 下车 下车
Stop! Piss off.
伤口要处理
l'm gonna have to take care of this.
怎么办?
What do you want to do?
找家医院 或兽医院 我会找我所需的
Get to a doctor or a veterinarian's office. l'll just boost what l need.
- 办得到吗? - 行 我有办法
- Could you do that? - Of course. l can do better.
- 情形如何? - 血流不止
- How is it? - l'm leaking.
对不起
l'm sorry.
那个女人出卖了我们
That girl sold us out.
她出卖了我们
She sold us out.
- 都准备好了? - 是的
- ls everything ready, Jean- Pierre? - Yes, everything.
- 帮个忙 - 好的
- Will you help me put my legs up? - Yeah.
轻点
Careful.
- 你确定你能办到? - 对
- Are you sure you can do this? - Yeah.
我曾用汤匙割掉一个人的盲肠
l once removed a guy's appendix with a grapefruit spoon.
- 来点酒 - 不了
- Have a drink? - No booze.
轻点、轻一点
Easy. Yeah.
看 子弹就在表皮下
lt's just below the surface.
好了 动手吧
All right, let's do it.
先用酒消毒
Let's just douse it with alcohol.
拿纱布擦掉血
Take the gauze and wipe away as much of the blood as you can.
我才能看清楚伤口
Keep it clean so l can see it.
手术很简单 我做过很多次
What we're gonna do is routine. l've done this many times before.
没伤及要害和动脉 放心吧
There are no vital organs or arteries. lt's okay.
死不了 夹紧再拨出子弹
You won't kill me. Just make sure you get the bullet before you pry it out.
- 好的 - 手术刀
- All right. - Take that scalpel.
握好刀柄
The upper part.
割下去 一小刀
Over here, just cut up there. Just a little cut.
好了
Okay. Try that.
拿镊子 用镊子撑开
Take the clamp. Take the clamp and open up the hole.
镊子放进去 放进去
Just put it in there.
对 就像这样 现在撑开镊子
Now open it up. Spread it.
好
Okay.
用另一个镊子夹出子弹
Now get the other clamps and get the bullet.
没夹紧别拨出来
Remember, don't take it out unless you really got it.
再试一次 再试一次
Do it again. Do it again, just try once more.
拨出后 马上按上纱布止血
When he pulls it out, put the gauze. There's gonna be a lot of blood.
按上纱布
Put the gauze there.
他妈的 子弹喷了铁氟龙
Fucker sprayed his bullet with Teflon.
他真的想干掉我 以绝后患
He was trying to stamp me "Paid in full."
- 防弹衣挡不住? - 是的
- ls that why it went through the vest? - Yeah.
能不能帮我缝伤口?
You think you could stitch me up on your own?
若不介意 我要昏倒了
lf you don't mind, l'm gonna pass out.
[ 巴黎 ]
- 你要杀我? - 不
- You gonna kill me? - No.
我不会杀你
l'm not gonna kill you.
为何要杀你?
Why would l want to kill you?
- 我把任务交给你了 - 我完成了任务
- l gave you a job. - l did my job.
怎么出了差错?
So how'd it go wrong?
我以为你要箱子
l thought what you wanted was the case.
我们会拿到箱子 对吗?
Oh, we'll get the case.
会拿到箱子 对吗? 葛格
We'll get the case, Gregor?
别担心箱子
Don't you worry about the case.
- 我要你解释清楚 - 解释? 解释什么?
- But l want an explanation. - An explanation? For what?
- 你搞砸了 - 我搞砸了?
- You bollixed it up. - l bollixed it up?
- 你雇用他的 - 通过你那该死的关系人!
- You hired him. - Through your fucking contact!
- 你太疏忽了 - 为何杀赖利?
- You didn't do your homework. - Why did you have to kill Larry?
他叫赖利?
Larry is it?
- 只是帮你收拾烂摊子 - 帮我?
- l was clearing up your mess. - My mess?
噢 那你来接手啊
Well, you take over then.
办不到吧? 是你在躲藏 不是吗?
But you can't, can you? lt's you that's hiding, isn't it, Seamus?
是你不敢露面
lt's you that can't show your face.
谁说的? 你跟谁谈过?
Who else thinks that? Who you been talking to?
所以才交给我办?
lsn't that the reason why l'm doing this job?
你是个好女孩
You're a good girl, Deirdre.
去完成任务吧
Do yourjob.
他不好惹
He's tough, your Yank.
没错
You're right about that.
他是谁?
But who is he?
不重要
That's not important.
中情局的?
Didn't he work for the ClA?
以前是
He used to.
现在不是?
Not anymore?
他在跑路
He's on the run.
确定?
You're sure?
我见过他 甚至见过他的本事
l know what he can do. l've seen him.
若他是中情局的人 何必自己动手术?
Why would he carve himself up if he were still ClA?
打个电话就能摆平
He makes a phone call, and it's taken care of.
你近来好吗?
And you? How have you been?
我们需要一些情报
We need some information.
我们要在巴黎找些人
We need to find some people in Paris.
找谁?
Who?
爱尔兰籍的一男一女...
An lrish man and woman...
和一位德籍前秘密警察
and a German, ex- KGB.
他们非常专业
They're professionals.
目前已匿藏起来
And they're in hiding.
对你而言很重要?
This is really important to you?
他救我一命
He saved my life.
好吧 我帮你找
l'll find them for you.
箱子呢?
Where's the case?
明天到
lt'll come tomorrow, l'm sure.
我相信是的 走吧
l'm sure it will, too. Let's go.
希望如此 否则你死定了
Let's hope so, for your sake anyway.
- 你好点了吗? - 能走动了
- Are you feeling better? - Yeah, enough to move around. Thanks.
我的嗜好 人都会老
My hobby. One grows old.
我很多朋友都想活着 去开家酒馆
A lot of fellas, friends of mine, just wanted to live to open a bar.
酒馆开成了吗?
Had they lived, would they have done it?
还是后来彻底觉醒了?
Then they were spared their disillusionment.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
他们是谁? 你的朋友?
Who were these people, friends of yours?
- 我不会伤害朋友 - 我是这样问吗?
- l wouldn't hurt a friend. - Was that my question?
是的
That's right.
那么
Well,
你是谁?
who are you?
跟你一样 想支持到退休
A fellow like you, trying to make it to retirement.
别到头来 好心却惹祸上身
At the end of the day, we're likely to be punished for our kindnesses.
别担心 我不会伤害你
You don't have to worry about me. l won't hurt you.
47名浪人 你知道吗?
The 47 ronin, do you know it?
他们的主人 因另一个君主的背叛而被杀
Forty- seven samurai whose master was betrayed and killed by another lord.
他们成了浪人 无主武士
They became ronin, masterless samurai,
因为另一个人的不忠 而背负耻辱之名
disgraced by another man's treachery.
他们计划了3年 假装当盗匪
For three years they plotted, pretending to be thieves,
雇庸兵、甚至装疯
mercenaries, even madmen.
我没空去做那些
That l didn't have time to do.
他们最后终于潜入城堡
And then one night they struck, slipping into the castle
杀了背叛的君主
of their lord's betrayer, killing him.
有意思 我和他们同行
Nice. l like that. My kind of job.
还有更精彩的
There's something more.
47人在城堡里
All 47 of them committed seppuku,
全体切腹自杀
ritual suicide, in the courtyard of the castle.
这我倒不赞同
Well, that l don't like so much.
但你能明白
But you understand it?
什么意思?
What do you mean "l understand it"?
战士标记
The warrior code.
驰骋沙场 这个你懂吗?
The delight in the battle. You understand that, yes?
不仅于此
But also something more.
你还身负重大使命
You understand there is something outside yourself that has to be served.
若背弃使命
And when that need is gone,
抛开信念 你还剩什么?
when belief has died, what are you?
无主的武士
A man without a master.
我现在是个没有薪水的人
Right now l'm a man without a paycheck.
浪人可侍奉别的君主
The Ronin could have hired themselves to new masters.
或图个人私利
They could have fought for themselves.
但他们选择荣誉、神秘
But they chose honor. They chose myth.
他们选错了
They chose wrong.
切...什么?
Seppu... What?
切腹
Seppuku.
切开腹部
Disembowelment.
刀从这里切下
The sword goes in here.
- 地址没错? - 错不了
- Are you sure this address is good? - Jean- Pierre gave it to me.
上次在河边
Under the bridge, by the river,
你怎么知道有伏击?
how did you know it was an ambush?
感觉有异 必有蹊跷
Whenever there is any doubt, there is no doubt.
这是第一课
That's the first thing they teach you.
谁教你的?
Who taught you?
不记得了 这是他们教的第二课
l don't remember. That's the second thing they teach you.
等待必有收获
All good things come to those who wait.
- 葛格怎么没死? - 箱子还没到手
- And why is Gregor still alive? - He's taking them to the package.
你好吗?
How you doing?
你是谁? 到底想怎样?
What are you? What are you gonna do to me?
冷静 再等一下
Let's just be calm for one more moment.
再等一下
One more moment.
为什么?
Why?
你知道为什么
Oh, you know why.
不 别乱来
No. You don't want to do that.
你下不了手
You can't.
回来!
Get back!
快上车
Get in the fucking car! Get in the car.
为何不杀她?
Why didn't you shoot her?
- 进隧道 - 噢 天啊!
- Take the tunnel now! - Oh, Christ!
快!
Come on!
混蛋
That fuck.
他到哪里去?
Where could he be?
俄国人、爱尔兰人都在找他 他会去哪?
The lrish are looking for him. The Russians are looking for him. So where does he go?
也许卖给俄国人
He goes to the Russians to make the deal for the case.
除非是安全交易 否则葛格不会现身
Gregor ain't coming in unless he can figure out a safe exchange.
他们都想杀了葛格而不付钱
He knows they'll kill him for the case rather than pay him for it.
葛格会在爱尔兰人找到他之前脱手
He's got to work it out soon before the lrish find him.
他会去哪里?
So where does he go?
他熟悉之处
You go to what you know.
他是前秘密警察 当然躲回老巢
He's KGB. He goes to one of his old safe houses.
老巢被剿了
No, they're all blown.
他会去哪里?
Where does he go?
假如
So?
换作是你 你去哪? 嗯?
You're on the run. Where do you go?
他以前曾到过哪里?
Where's he been?
用假箱子掉包
He made the fake case.
他做了假箱子
He had the fake case made.
葛格
Gregor.
他做了假箱子 事先做好的
He had it made. He had to have had it made.
在巴黎 没到尼斯之前
ln Paris, before we went to Nice.
他没时间做
He didn't have time to have it made.
找类似的箱子喷漆
He bought something that looked like it, then he spray- painted it.
哪来的漆? 他没离开过
Where did he get this paint? He never left the room.
假箱子哪来的?
Where did he get the case?
装溜冰鞋的箱子
lt's a case for ice skates.
为何是溜冰鞋?
Why ice skates?
他怎么知道是装溜冰鞋的箱子?
And why would Gregor know an ice skate case?
他没时间做箱子
He didn't have time to have it made.
没时间做假箱子
He didn't have time to have the fake case made.
是俄国人做的
The Russians made it.
找错对象了
We're following the wrong people.
不必找葛格了
We don't have to find Gregor.
俄国人能带我们找到他
lf we find the Russians, they will take us to him.
来巴黎多年 你人面很广
You've lived in Paris a long time. You know the people.
还好
l get around.
那些新来的俄国移民
You meet the new Russians.
间谍、特务都变成黑社会
You know how it is. Ex- spies. Now it's Mafia.
受政治保护
Under diplomatic cover.
你是秘密警察?
KGB?
以前是
Ex- KGB.
以前有权势、豪赌、财富、房车
Heavy hitters. Gamblers. Lots of money. Big cars.
像沙皇一样挥金如土
They live like Tsars, throw money away.
昂贵的貂皮帽
Fur hats are expensive.
还有保镖
And bodyguards.
昂贵的大衣 齐瓦哥医生
Expensive coats. Dr. Zhivago.
我很忙 没空
l have a lot of work. No time.
我了解
l understand.
好吧 走
All right. Let's go.
搞定了
lt's going to be fine.
他去打听了
The guy is gonna reach out.
可靠吗?
ls he any good?
他熟悉巴黎的俄国人...
Jean- Pierre says if it's Russian and it's in Paris...
要在巴黎找俄国人...
lf l wanted to find Russians in Paris this week...
我会去"冰上芭蕾馆"找
l would go to the ice show.
[ 娜塔莎- 基诺娃表演 ]
用情报跟你换支烟
l'll trade you a favor for a cigarette.
离他们远点
The favor is, steer clear of those guys.
那些俄国人?
The Russians?
他们出手阔绰
They sure throw money around here.
娜塔莎- 基诺娃
俄国人都来看娜塔莎表演
The Russian is seeing this Natacha Kirilova, star of the ice show.
每晚都来
He spends every evening in the audience.
- 你怎么知道? - 我们是高中同学
- How the hell did you find that out? - We went to high school together.
米基 还好吗?
Mikhi, is everything all right?
很好
Everything is fine.
甜心
Sweet girl.
快去吧
Go. Go on.
各位先生女士...
Ladies and gentlemen...
很荣幸介绍...
we are very proud to present...
两届奥运冠军...
two- time Olympic champion...
三届世界冠军...
and three- time world champion...
娜塔莎- 基诺娃!
Natacha Kirilova!
走
Let's go.
在这里等
Wait out here.
他来了
Yes, he is.
你好 米基
Hello, Mikhi.
还没到约定时间
The meet is not till later tonight.
到了
The meet is now.
钱带来了吗?
You have the money?
我们打算赴约之前拿
Well, you know, we were going to go back to get it before the meet.
我不认为
l don't think so.
钱带来了?
You have the money?
钱带来了 箱子呢?
l might have the money. Where is the case?
不 你去吧 我下不了手
No, you have to do it. l couldn't live with myself.
钱带来了
l have the money.
我们就在这里解决
We conclude this now and part friends.
好吗?
Okay?
箱子呢?
Where is the case?
钱先给我
l'd like to be paid now.
当然
No doubt.
接下来呢?
Now tell me the other part.
接下来?
The other part?
我走人
l'm leaving.
拿了钱走人
l'm taking my fee and l'm leaving.
看台上有个狙击手
l have a person with a rifle in the stadium.
我的老友 从不失手
l've worked with her for years. She never misses.
我会回电
l will call.
45秒内回电 告知我要离开
l have to call within 45 seconds to say that l'm leaving.
10分钟后报平安
And then in another 10 minutes to say that l'm safe.
若我没回电 娜塔莎死定了
Should l be unable to call, your friend will be shot.
还有30秒
30 seconds, Mikhi.
找人
We have to see somebody inside.
没证件、不能进
You can't pass without badges.
20秒
20 seconds.
10秒
10 seconds.
有两个人 要找俄国人
There were two of them. They were looking for those guys.
等一下
Just a minute, sir.
我是智利公民 你看护照
l am a Chilean citizen, as you can see from my passport.
妈妈!
Mama!
跟着他
Stay with him.
走 快走!
Get out of here! Get out of here!
下车 离开这里
Get out of the car. Walk away! Walk away! Walk away!
快、快走!
Go. Go.
- 你也跟我走吧 - 快走
- l will if you will. - Just go.
跟我走 别管箱子
Come with me. Forget about the case.
我要找你老板 不是箱子
l didn't come for the case. l came for your boss.
我来抓希蒙斯的
l came for Seamus. l came for him.
快离开
Just get out of here.
我没离职 明白吗?
l never left. Don't you see?
让开、让路!
Get out of the way!
让路
车子过不去 路封了
You can't pass this way. lt's blocked.
我可以抓你 或杀了你
l can take you in or leave you here.
是他拿箱子的
There. That's him with the case.
- 先生 站住 - 等等、等一下
- Sir, over here, please. - Wait, wait.
歹徒都在外面!
There are more back there!
站住、别动
All right. Stay where you are! Don't move.
闭嘴 别出声!
Shut your fucking mouth up! Shut your mouth!
你这蠢货
You stupid shite.
你死定了
You're a dead man.
现在报导国际新闻
This is the BBC World Service.
北爱尔兰历经
It was announced today, after almost 30 years
30年流血内战
of bIoody and seemingIy intractabIe civil conflict in Northern lreland
新教徒政府
that a peace agreement has been reached
与爱尔兰反抗军...
between the predominantIy Protestant government of that British- ruIed encIave
终于达成和平协议
and the lrish resistance.
...据CNN报导
...have told CNN that it was the apprehension
爱尔兰恐怖份子
and sIaying in France
希蒙斯在法国被杀 凶手逃逸
of the lrish terrorist Seamus O'Rourke by parties stiII unknown
和平协议得以顺利达成
that contributed a stabiIity, IargeIy aIIowing the negotiations
这是历史性的一刻
to proceed to their historic concIusion today.
之前报道过
O'Rourke had earlier been denounced
希蒙斯被爱尔兰共和军
by the lRA, the military wing of Sinn Fein,
开除军籍
as a rogue breakaway operative.
我很高兴认识你
Well then, good knowing you.
- 什么? - 你说什么?
- l'm sorry? - You said something.
我说 她不会回来了
l said she would not be coming back here.
对
Yeah.
她不会回来了 是吗?
She would not be coming back here, would she?
我的手无法拿钱付帐
l can't even put my hand in my pocket to pay the bill.
我请客
l'll get it.
下回我请
l'll get the next one.
箱子里装什么?
What was in the case?
我忘了
l don't remember.
这是第二课
Lesson number two.
保持联系
Keep in touch.
走吧
Let's go.
纳言敏行
No questions. No answers.
这是行规
That's the business we're in.
还要随遇而安
You accept it and move on.
也许 这就是第三课
Maybe that's Iesson number three.